<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Tanay Kashyap</title>
    <link>https://iamtanay.github.io/portfolio/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Tanay Kashyap</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamtanay.github.io/portfolio/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Python Project: Analyzing a Youtube channel using Streamlit</title>
      <link>https://iamtanay.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamtanay.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-2/</guid>
      <description>In this project we built a dashboard using Streamlit for analyzing a Youtube channel. We made the dashboard to analyze the entire Youtube channel as well as individual videos.
After building the dashboard we also successfully published it online using Share by Streamlit feature. This is an interactive dashboard which can help you design the same for your Youtube channel.
The data we used was sourced from Kaggle. We analyzed Ken Jee&amp;rsquo;s Youtube channel and presented the statistics to visualize the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Project: Predicting hotel booking cancellations</title>
      <link>https://iamtanay.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamtanay.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-1/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we built a machine learning model to predict whether or not a customer cancelled a hotel booking.
We will use a dataset on hotel bookings from the article &amp;ldquo;Hotel booking demand datasets&amp;rdquo;, published in the Elsevier journal, Data in Brief. The abstract of the article states
This data article describes two datasets with hotel demand data. One of the hotels (H1) is a resort hotel and the other is a city hotel (H2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocket Science: Designing a model rocket using OpenRocket and simulating to analyze the results</title>
      <link>https://iamtanay.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamtanay.github.io/portfolio/projects/project-3/</guid>
      <description>In this project we designed a model rocket using OpenRocket software to the specifications provided below:
Wet mass : 700 gms(minimum)
Body tube outer diameter : 4.5 cm - 6 cm
Body tube thickness : 0.3 cm
Body tube material : Cardboard
Flight computer mass : 150 gm
Flight computer width : 2.8 cm
Flight computer length : 16 cm
Avionics Bay, Nose Cone, Motor Mount, Fins Material : PLA</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
